He's done with Hollywood.
I'm Still Here is a music, comedy, drama film directed by Casey Affleck.
I'm Still Here is a portrayal of a tumultuous year in
the life of actor Joaquin Phoenix.
With remarkable access, the film follows the Oscar-nominee as he announces his retirement from a
successful film career in the fall of 2008 and sets off to reinvent himself as a hip-hop musician.
The film is a portrait of an artist at a crossroads and explores notions of courage and
creative reinvention, as well as the ramifications of a life spent in the public eye.
Joaquin Phoenix, played by Joaquin Phoenix.
Anton, played by Antony Langdon.
Play Director, played by Carey Perloff.
Larry McHale, played by Larry McHale.
Casey Affleck, played by Casey Affleck.
Jack Nicholson, played by Jack Nicholson.
I'm Still Here is a 2010 American mockumentary musical parody film directed
by Casey Affleck, and written by Affleck and Joaquin Phoenix.
The film follows the real life of Phoenix from the announcement of his retirement
from acting through his transition into a career as a hip hop artist.
Throughout the filming period, Phoenix remained in character for public appearances,
giving many the impression that he was genuinely pursuing a new career.
The film explores themes of hip-hop, mockumentary, movie
star, duringcreditsstinger, marihuana.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.